how to enable cost control strategies
for business Central Telemetry when you
enable Telemetry for business Central it
is important just like any other as a
resource that you control the cost of
this it cost data to ingest data into
Telemetry and it costs to uh keep it for
longer than the default retention policy
so how do you see uh the cost of your
telemeter resource well you go to the
menu here on the left and you scroll
down a bit under uh until you find the
configure menu here and under the
configure menu you find usage and
estimated costs if I click this I will
be able to see an overview of my monthly
payments now this is a new resource so
it just says zero but once you have data
here you um you will be able to see see
your monthly
costs now the first thing that is
important is that you set a daily cap of
the Telemetry you re you ingest so here
under the daily cap uh button if I click
that I can Define how many gigabytes or
megabytes of data would I like to ingest
per day for application insights the
first I believe it's four gigabytes a
month is free and after that you pay for
your ingestion so in the beginning maybe
simply set 100 megabytes or
0.1 so 100 megabytes per day or whatever
your daily cap is and uh and make sure
that you have a warning if you start
exceeding that because that means if you
get a warning it means that there is
data that you not not getting anymore so
click okay here and now you have set up
a daily cap uh and you're good to
[Music]
go